Injured individuals, go and find the sorcerer!
受傷的人快去找術士！
Others, step back!
其他人都退下！
He, as the main force of the subjugation unit,
作為討伐隊主力的
is about to arrive!
那個“他”就要來了！
He is the hidden ace of the church.
他是教會的隱藏王牌
He has conquered countless obstacles
他曾跨越無數絕境
and experienced many battles.
身經百戰
He's the Calamity Crusher,
他就是“災厄殲滅者”
Shagrua Edith Lugrid!
夏古魯亞．艾迪斯．路古利特
This maze
這座迷宮
is still expanding.
還在不斷擴大
The crazed undead summoned
那具發狂的喪屍召集來的死者
so many dead bodies
其數量之多
that they even overflowed out of the maze.
甚至溢出到了迷宮外面
It is the rare necromancer,
它就是稀世的死靈術士
known as the Corpse God!
人稱屍神殿！
(Dead Mount, Dead Play)
《屍體如山的死亡遊戲》
Oh, God.
神明啊
This is such a powerful magic.
這是何等強大的魔力
If we cannot defeat it here,
若是不能在這裡將它擊潰
the world will be devoured by tide of the undead.
世界將會被屍潮所吞噬
However,
不過
can Sir Shagrua, who bears the name of Calamity Crusher,
背負“災厄殲滅者”之名的 夏古魯亞大人
He can definitely make it.
他一定可以的
Sir Shagrua will never lose.
夏古魯亞大人是不會輸的
He will
他是
never
絕不會向死亡屈服的
I was killed by you.
我是被你害死的
We were all killed by you.
我們都是被你害死的
Why are you the only one who survived?
為什麼只有你活了下來
Go die.
你也去死吧
Go die and suffer the torment.
去死 去遭受痛苦的折磨
Struggle desperately and cry in pain.
拚命掙扎 痛哭吧
Let out endless screams of sorrow.
發出無盡的悲鳴吧
I was able to see the souls
我看到了
of those whose lives you had taken.
被你奪去性命的那些人的靈魂
You possess the Evil Eye?
你是擁有“亞眼”的人嗎
Evil Eye?
“亞眼”？
Those who possess the Evil Eye
擁有“亞眼”的人
are able to see spirits.
與生俱來便能夠看到靈魂
No matter if it's a robber or
不論是自己殺掉的強盜或者魔物
or even
甚至就連
a bird or insect strangled to death, none can escape the Evil Eye possessor.
掐死的飛鳥或是羽虱 都逃不過亞眼擁有者
Therefore, most Evil Eye possessors
故而大部分擁有亞眼的人
would hide in the church to spend their lives.
都會躲進教會度過自己的一生
Yet some would be immersed in the pleasure of manipulating souls
還有的人則是沉浸於玩弄靈魂的快感
and become necromancers
成為和“屍神殿”一樣的死靈術士
But Sir Shagrua chose to step
但是夏古魯亞大人為了我們 選擇踏上戰場 英勇奮戰
That is
那就是
your true form?
你的本體嗎
Is everything you do just for this little thing?
你所做的一切就是為了這個小玩意嗎
All life is nothing but a toy to me.
所有的生命都不過是玩具
Are you regarding yourself as a death god?
你是把自己當作死神了嗎
The gods do not play games.
神明不玩遊戲
Just like you and me who possess the Evil Eye.
就像擁有亞眼的你我一樣
You actually enjoy it, don't you?
你其實挺享受的吧
You enjoy the sorrowful cries filled with resentment
享受那些被自己殺掉的人的靈魂
from the souls you have killed.
所發出的飽含怨恨的悲嘆
Don't confuse me with you.
別把我跟你混為一談
You monster who is not worth pitying!
你這個死不足惜的怪物
You and I are futilely fighting to death,
像我和你這種胡亂玩弄生命的人
but we are just wearing the skin of the Grim Reaper,
都不過是披著死神的外皮
At the end of the day, we are just playing house.
說到底 我們就只是 在玩這種“扮家家酒”而已
This pattern
這種咒紋
is a magic that I have never seen before.
是我沒見過的魔法
Let's put an end to this.
我們來做個了斷吧
Our game ends here.
我和你的遊戲到此為止
You won't succeed.
你休想得逞
As long as you still exist,
只要你還存在
there would be no future
這個國家
for this country
還有孩子們
and the children.
就沒有未來
Let me help you.
我來支援你
Sir Shagrua!
夏古魯亞大人
My memory is a bit fuzzy.
我的記憶感覺有些模糊
By the way,
對了 那時候
was my magic activated back then?
我的魔法發動了嗎
What is this place?
這是哪裡
My body can still move.
我的身體還能動
What's the matter with these slender arms?
這纖細的手臂是怎麼回事
Why can't I make any sound?
我為什麼無法好好發出聲音
The floor and walls are a bit strange.
地板和牆壁都有點奇怪
What is going on here? This street…
這條街 到底是怎麼一回事…
Hey! Hey!
喂喂喂喂
Wait a moment.
等一下等一下等一下
Darn. Seriously?
不是吧 真的假的
My head broke down,
我的腦袋
didn't it?
終於還是壞掉了嗎
It's me. Stop the disposal operation.
是我 停止回收行動
The body in the alley is gone now.
巷子裡的屍體已經沒有了
More precisely, he is still alive.
準確地來說他還活著
What exactly is going on?
到底是怎麼回事
Was it that she didn't make it?
難道說她失手了嗎
No way. I've checked it.
不 我之前確認過了
Anyway, don't take any action for now.
總之 先不要採取行動
Why can that guy
為什麼那傢伙
still walk normally
在喉嚨被割開的狀態下
even when his throat is cut open?
還能正常地行走啊
It's simply inexplicable.
簡直莫名其妙
All of them are architectural styles that I have never seen before.
這些全都是我從未見過的建築樣式
The characters I have never seen before.
還有我從未見過的文字
Is that
那是…
a projection technique?
投影術式嗎
But I didn't sense any magic.
可是我並未感知到魔力
What place is this exactly?
這裡究竟是什麼地方
SHINJUKU STATION
(新宿站)
By the way, there are really a lot of people here.
話雖如此 這裡人可真多啊
The kids look great.
孩子們的表情都很棒
They are laughing happily.
他們都笑得很開心
This must be a place where life is peaceful.
這裡一定是個生活安穩的地方
What happened to that country later?
那個國家後來怎麼樣了
Although I don't know if I can go back,
雖說不知道我還能不能回去
I hope that country can at least have a future.
但我希望那個國家至少能擁有未來
Can I take up some of your time?
可以佔用你一點時間嗎
We received a report that
我們接到了通報
there is a strange-looking teenager here.
說是有一名樣子奇怪的少年
Can you understand what we are saying?
你能聽懂我們說的話嗎
-Are you alone? Where are you from? -What language are they speaking?
-你是一個人嗎 你是從哪裡來的 -他們說的是什麼語言
-Can you tell us? -But I understand some words.
-可以告訴我們嗎 -但有些地方我倒是能聽懂
Am I extracting linguistic information
難道我正在從我這具身體的腦髓當中
from the brain of this body?
抽取語言方面的資訊嗎
The blood on the clothes is not some kind of pattern, is it?
衣服上的血應該不是花紋吧
Are you okay?
你還好嗎
Can you tell me your name?
你能說出自己的名字嗎
This is a language called Japanese.
這是稱作日語的語言啊
This body's name is Polka Shinoyama.
我的這具身體的名字是四乃山波爾卡
Is he the child of foreign tourists?
他是外國遊客的孩子嗎
He suffered a serious injury to his throat.
他喉嚨受了很嚴重的傷
It seems like the bleeding has stopped.
血看起來倒是止住了
I will call an ambulance…
我立刻去叫救護車…
Great, it turns out you're okay.
太好了 原來你沒事啊
Who are you?
你是？
The police are troublesome, aren't they?
警察很麻煩對吧
Let's escape.
總之我們先逃再說吧
Wait…
等…
Hey, stop there!
喂 你們給我站住
It seems like something happened, Mr. Iwa.
好像發生了什麼事啊 岩野目先生
On the streets of Shinjuku, it would be strange if nothing happens.
在新宿的街頭上 無論發生什麼事都不奇怪
Right, Ara?
你說是吧 荒瀨
Yeah.
你說得也對
Okay, we should go back now.
好啦 我們該回去了
Okay.
好
We seem to have escaped successfully.
我們貌似是順利逃了出來
Do you remember who I am?
喂喂 你還記得我是誰嗎？
I'm Misaki Sakimiya.
我是崎宮美咲
If you read it backwards, it would be Sakimiya Misaki.
倒過來唸是美咲崎宮
What's the point of reading it backwards?
倒過來唸有什麼意義嗎？
The memories related to this girl
我的腦海裡逐漸浮現出
gradually emerged in my mind.
跟這個女孩有關的記憶
Ah, she is smiling.
啊 她在笑
It seems that she is a friend
她好像認識這具身體的主人
What are you doing?
妳這是在做什麼
Physical examination.
身體檢查？
Bezical ezaminasion?
身體檢查是什麼？
Uh, your body is still warm.
嗯 你身體很溫暖
Your feet are also there.
腳也還在
Don't worry.
別擔心
You're not a ghost
你不是幽靈
and you're doing just fine.
而且你還活得好好的
Great!
太好了
Uh, thank you.
那個 真是謝謝妳
Oh my, you are too polite.
哎呀哎呀
-After all… -No, you helped me. I have to thank you.
-畢竟 -不不 妳幫了我 我得謝謝妳
Next,
接下來我還得
I have to kill you again.
再殺你一次嘛
What?
妳說什麼？
Just now, I clearly used this
我說
Why are you still alive?
為什麼你現在還活著呢
Shit.
糟了
Unexpectedly, it's this girl.
竟然是這個女孩
She killed the owner of this body.
殺掉了這具身體的主人
Is he Polka Shinoyama?
他就是“四乃山波爾卡”嗎
Although he is only a 16-year-old kid,
明明只是個16歲的小鬼
someone hired an assassin to kill him.
卻有人雇傭殺手追殺他
What exactly is Misaki's
美咲的雇主到底是在盤算著什麼
Anyway, this time, you have to die.
不管了 這次你一定要死掉喔
If not, we, the disposal agency,
要是沒死掉的話 我們“回收站”
wouldn't be able to get paid.
可就拿不到報酬了
No way. Only running away has already exhausted all my energy.
不行 光是逃跑我就已經竭盡全力
But speaking of which, what exactly is the situation here?
不過話說回來 這裡究竟是什麼情況
It's almost imperceptible to sense the presence of elves.
幾乎感知不到精靈的氣息
The magical elements in the air are also very scarce.
空氣裡的魔素也十分稀薄
Plus, this body has almost
再加上這具身體
no magic power.
幾乎沒有魔力
In this way, I cannot heal any new injury at all.
如此一來我根本無法治癒新傷
What should I do?
我該怎麼做才好
And also,
說起來 我根本就記不清
I can't remember why I became like this.
自己為什麼會變成這樣
I will definitely die if I get
我只要再受到一次致命傷
if I get another fatal injury.
我毫無疑問就會死掉
Alright.
好啦
The time for playing hide-and-seek is over now.
捉迷藏的時間到此結束囉
Wow, amazing!
好厲害好厲害
It's the first time I've met someone who can dodge my attacks.
這還是頭一次遇到 有人能避開我的攻擊呢
I seem to be
我
getting a little excited.
好像有點興奮起來了
I can react,
我雖然能做出反應
but my body cannot keep up.
但身體卻跟不上
Are you kidding me?
開什麼玩笑
The long-awaited world
實現我一心嚮往的世界的線索
seems to be right in front of me.
明明就在我的眼前啊
At that time, I was not able to grasp it.
那時候我沒能把握住
Now that I have come this far,
現在都走到這一步了
how could I possibly give up?
我怎麼可能放棄
Amazing.
你真厲害
Although I have killed
雖然我殺了不少黑道上的人和殺手
it's the first time someone has ever overwhelmed me with its aura.
但我可是第一次 在氣勢上被人壓過一頭
I couldn't help but start to like you.
我不禁有點喜歡上你了
Here is…
這裡是…
This building is very famous
這棟大樓
among my peers.
在同行間很出名喔
In the underworld,
在黑道那裡
this building is famous as the "execution ground".
這棟大樓是有名的“處刑場”
They will dissolve people here.
他們好像還會把人給溶解掉呢
The power of science is very powerful, isn't it?
科學的力量很厲害吧
And it is said that
還有啊
ghosts or people from the underworld
據說這裡經常有 幽靈或是黑道上的人現身
so it's impossible for anyone to come over.
所以幾乎沒有人敢過來這裡呢
Putting aside the people in the underworld,
黑道上的人暫且不論
ghosts are very powerful
幽靈可是很厲害的
due to their supernatural and mysterious abilities.
他們是源自超自然的神秘力量喔
I found that
看來妳說得沒錯
even with the eyes of this body,
即便是用這具身體的眼睛
I can see it clearly.
我也能看得一清二楚
Isn't the way those guys
使用這裡的那幫傢伙
treat other people's lives here
對待他人生命的方式 是不是太隨意了
I see. Even this body can see
原來如此 即便我使用的是這具身體
the spirits,
我也能夠看到人的靈魂
which means
這樣也就表示
that the Evil Eye is not a power attached to the eyeballs and brain,
亞眼跟眼球和腦髓沒有關係
but to the soul.
是附著在靈魂上的力量啊
Hey, what's wrong?
嘻嘻 怎麼了怎麼了
Are you the kind of person
你是那種珍惜生命的人？
That's right.
沒錯
You should
妳也是
also cherish life more.
妳也應該更加珍視生命才對
I think so too.
我也是這麼認為的呢
After all, human life is heavier than the Earth.
畢竟人類的性命可是比地球還要重的
It's 21 grams, isn't it?
我記得好像是21克吧？
So this time,
所以這一次
I won't leave you with even a gram.
我一克都不會給你留下
I will kill you
我會細心周到地
carefully and thoughtfully!
將你殺掉
You are not allowed to recklessly tread on lives like this.
不許妳如此輕率地冒犯生命
All lives
所有的生命
are my toys.
都是我的玩具
Do not underestimate lives.
我不許妳輕視生命
Huh?
什麼？
What's wrong with you?
您這是怎麼了
Nothing.
沒事
I'm just worried about
我只是在擔心自己
whether I have completed the task.
有沒有完成任務
What are you saying?
您在說什麼啊
The records you have achieved
您立下的戰績 無愧於“災厄殲滅者”的名號
Sir Shagrua.
夏古魯亞大人
At the moment when my sword was about to pierce that guy,
在我的劍刺向那傢伙的最後一瞬間
he did cast a spell.
它的確發動了魔法
It seemed to be the teleportation magic.
感覺很像是轉移魔法
Although I did use my Evil Eye to capture its soul at the time,
雖說那時 我的確用亞眼 捕捉到了那傢伙的靈魂
its speed of dissipation
可是它消散的速度 未免也太快了
Did I really eliminate the Corpse God,
我真的將“屍神殿”
the necromancer?
也就是那名死靈術士 我真的把他給消滅掉了嗎
I just received the report
我剛才收到了教會觀測班的報告
The aura of the Corpse God spirit
“屍神殿”靈魂的氣息
has completely disappeared from this world.
已經完全從這個世界裡消失了
You saved the world,
您拯救了這個世界
Sir Shagrua.
夏古魯亞大人
I hope so.
希望如此
My mind is gradually becoming clear.
我的頭腦逐漸變得清醒
It's full of magic now.
魔力也補滿了
I am now able to think.
我總算可以好好思考了
Your name is Misaki, right?
妳是叫美咲對吧？
Although I am not sure
雖說我不清楚
why you wanted to kill the owner of this body,
妳為什麼要將“這具身體”的主人
named Polka Shinoyama,
“四乃山波爾卡”殺掉
I still want to
可是我
thank you.
仍然想要向妳道謝
Thank you
謝謝妳
for bringing me
帶我來到這種充滿了魔力的地方
In this world,
在這裡的話 說不定我能夠得到
a stable life.
平穩的生活
The time for playing hide-and-seek should indeed come to an end.
捉迷藏的時間確實該結束了
I won't run away anymore.
我不會再逃了
The next thing would be the "Death God Game"
接下來就是
where you and I
我和妳之間
will fight to death.
以命相搏的“死神遊戲”了
Okay, let's continue.
好了 讓我們繼續吧
Poor assassin,
可憐的暗殺者啊
how long do you plan to pretend to be at sleep?
妳打算裝睡到什麼時候
D-Did she die?
已 已經死掉了？
(Episode 2: The New World)
(第2集 The New World -異世界-)